我们是阴影
We are the shadows
或是烟雾 我们患难与共
and the smoke, we rise.
我们是鬼魂 隐藏...
We are the ghosts that hide...
...在夜色中
...in the night.
(索马里 亚丁湾)
人质在我们手上太久了
三个月了
太久了
有人
要为此付出代价
你们公司有足够的时间付钱
可你们不在乎
不顾他们的死活
不救他们
我们也不在乎
他们的死
都是你们
造成的
别开枪！ 别开枪！
Don't shoot me.
什么人?
Who is that?
包里是钱 把人质放了
There's your money. Release the hostages.
多少钱
How much in there?
- 300万 - 太晚了 现在我们要500万了
- Three. - You're too late. We want $5 million.
死到临头还这么贪
Fuck, it's humid!
最后一次机会
Last chance!
要还是不要
Take it or leave it.
放心
All at ease!
坐下 根拿
Take a seat, Gunner.
嘿 你们只会光说不做
Hey, you're all cannon and no balls!
给我们500万 快
We want the money now!
- 这是警告 - 别！
- Warning shot. - No!
打低了
A little low.
拉灯！
Lights out!
我杀了他！你们再动 我就杀了他！
I'll kill him! I swear I'll kill him!
我建议你放了人质
If I were you, I'd take this opportunity to leave.
你怎么想?坚持一下?
What's your call? You stayin'?
嗯 试试吧
Yeah, we tried.
老子把他们全杀了！绝不手软
I'll kill them all! I don't care.
这世上傻子太多了 所以住手吧
There's more fools in this world than people. So back off, cuz.
你住嘴！
You back off!
反正你左右是个死 所以我闭嘴
You know, you're gonna be dead anyway. So I'm gonna shut up.
最后一次机会 放了人质
Last chance. Let the hostages go
不然你就完蛋啦
or you're out of there.
把钱拿过来 拿到这儿来…
Bring the money here to me.
我自己还缺钱呢
I need the money myself.
左边四个交给我
I'll take the four on the left.
哦 又来了
Oh, here we go.
右边两个是你的 剩下的人交给我
Why don't you take the two on the right and leave the rest alone?
老子把他们全杀了！
I'll kill them all!
你该盯住右边那两个 你的身手不行了
You should take the two on the right. You're not that fast anymore.
只有闪电才能快过我
The only thing faster is lightning.
“闪电” 真行
"Light!" Get original!
子弹肯定比刀快
Bullets go faster than blades.
我们走着瞧！
We'll see.
马上把钱拿过来！
Bring the money here! Now!
想要钱吗?
You want the money?
自己过来拿
Go get it.
干掉他们！
Kill them!
- 嘿 我们打平了 - 作梦吧你
- I call that a tie. - Come on, keep dreaming.
省省吧 伙计们
A little compassion, folks.
我猜你一个也没打中
You know, I don't think you hit one of them.
事实上 你的刀也不怎么样
I don't see any knives, actually.
现在300万还能买啥
Three million doesn't buy much nowadays.
你们在干什么?
How are you guys doing?
- 他在那干嘛? - 吊海盗
- What the hell is he doing? - Hanging a pirate.
别开玩笑
Don't be ridiculous.
根拿! 你在那干嘛?
Gunner! What are you doing?
吊海盗
Hanging a pirate!
- 真是个神经病 - 这可不好
- That is seriously demented. - This is no good.
不是像你认为的那样
but put one in Speed Racer's shoulder. Not that you'd feel it, but put one in Speed Racer's shoulder.
- 你自己拿主意 - 真够义气
- You're on your own. - Appreciate it.
有朋友真好
It's good to have friends.
- 根拿 - 干嘛
- Gunner. - Yeah?
这不是我们的风格 放了他
This isn't how we work. Let him go.
为什么?换作他 也会这样对付我们
Why? He'd do it to us.
你知道这样做不太正常 对不对
You know what you're doing is a little crazy, right?
那是他的问题
That's his problem.
那也是你的问题 别发疯！
It's your problem, too. It's a little sick.
嘿 别碰我的钱
Hey, don't touch my money.
根拿 最后一次机会
Gunner, last chance.
放了他 否则开除你
Let him go or we're letting you go.
吊海盗没有错 这是维京传统
It's good to hang pirates. Old Viking custom.
这根本不是维京传统
It isn't an old Viking custom at all.
我们不用那种方式杀人
We don't kill like that.
是吗?不够文雅?
Yeah? Not polite enough?
- 放了他 根拿 - 你最近怎么样 巴尼?
- Let him go, Gunner. - How are you doing, Barney?
非常好
Pretty good.
我这位哥们刚用钢头靴踢了我
My partner here kicked me with steel-tipped boots.
- 你说荒不荒唐 - 你活该
- Can you believe that? - You deserved it.
我想可能要缝两针
I think I'll need stitches.
也许
Maybe.
- 我恨缝针 - 我们都恨
- I hate stitches. - Everyone does.
放了他 根拿
Let him go, Gunner.
放了他?
Let him go?
放了他
Let him go.
- 他现在冷静了吗? - 去吧
- Think he's cool? - Go.
根拿 你不会犯混吧?
Gunner, you cool?
不会
Yeah.
不用 你留着吧
No, keep it.
你懂刀
You appreciate a good blade.
来啦
Coming!
哪一个?
Who is it?
有一天 你会遇上一个对你一往情深的男人
Someday you'll find a man who'll be happy just to watch you sleep.
- 我不知道你回来了 - 你好 宝贝
- Hi. I didn't know you were back. - Hey, babe.
我刚回来
Yeah, I just arrived.
- 嘿 - 你看起来棒极了
- Hey. - You look great.
你应该给我打个电话
I wish you would have called.
打电话我不在行
I've never been a good caller.
你一个月都没和我联系
I haven't heard from you in over a month.
真的吗?时间过的真快 你说是吗?
Really? Time flies, huh?
下不为例！对不起
Won't happen again! Sorry.
不过 给你一个惊喜
But I do have a surprise.
玫瑰味的 你的最爱
Rose-flavored. Your favorite.
还有一件东西送给你
And I did have something else for you.
是我在缅甸为你选的
It's something I picked up from Burma.
一颗红宝石
It's a ruby.
颜色很漂亮 不过灯光太暗 有点看不出来
It's a good color, but it's hard to see in this light.
在商店买的时候 看起来很闪
This kind of looked a little shinier when I bought it in the shop, you know?
赖斯 没事吧?
Lace, everything all right?
- 没事 - 他是谁?
- Yeah. - Who is he?
一个朋友
He's a friend.
天很晚了 你叫什么名字?
Kind of late. You got a name?
朋友 她刚刚说了
Friend. She just told you.
李 别这样
Lee, come on.
别这样 李 对不起
Don't leave like this. Lee, I'm sorry.
我以为我们相处的很不错
I thought things were good between us.
我觉得你不关心我 也不想让我了解你
I felt like you never cared about getting in my life or letting me into yours.
- 别走 - 没错 你说的一点不错
- Stop. - Yeah, sure I did.
不 彼此认真对待的话不应该是这样
No. Not the way two people who are serious about each other do.
我认识你已经一年半了
I have known you for over a year and a half,
可我连你是干什么的都不知道
and I don't even know what you do for a living.
这有什么关系? 我对你一心一意 这就足够了
What's it matter? When I'm here, I'm with you. That matters.
可事实是 你对我心不在焉
That matters, but when you're here, you're not really here.
你没对我说话 你根本就没和我交心
Okay? You don't talk to me. You don't open up to me.
我真不知道你会这么想
I have no idea what you're feeling.
你送我礼物 非常漂亮的礼物 但我想要的是你！
You bring me presents. They're beautiful presents but I want you!
你是个好人 我爱你 可…
You're a good man. I love you, but...
- 赖斯！ - 我讨厌这个人的声音
- Lace! - I hate his voice.
- 你说什么? - 别让他过来
- Did you say something? - Don't let him come down here.
你说什么?
Did you say something?
- 别让他… - 保罗 等我一下 行吗
- Do not let... - Paul, just give me a second, okay?
李 我很抱歉
Lee, I'm sorry.
告诉我 你明白我说的话
Please tell me you understand what I'm saying.
- 你一定得理解我 - 我理解
- You have to understand. - I understand.
- 你多保重 - 保重
- You take care. - Take care.
他不是好人 赖斯
He's no good, Lace.
兄弟 你是不是从来不睡觉?
Hey, brother, don't you ever sleep?
这位是我朋友…
This is my friend...
你叫什么来着 宝贝?
What's your name again, baby?
- 夏安 - 夏安
- Cheyenne. - Cheyenne.
夏安 阿拉帕霍 切诺基 波尼
Cheyenne, Arapaho, Cherokee, Pawnee.
想喝一杯吗?
You want a drink?
不用了
I'm good.
宝贝 上楼…
Why don't you run upstairs
为我调一杯超强的 加六颗橄榄的马提尼 好吗?
and get me one of them super-duper six-olive martinis, baby?
- 让我干什么都行 宝贝 - 会让你满意的
- Anything for you, baby. - You got it.
- 小妞 喜欢我 - 就像前面50个
- Got a crush on me. - Like the last 50.
兄弟 妞越多越好
Hey, brother, who's counting?
- 奶奶的 你看起来不错 - 瞧瞧你
- Damn, you look good. - Look at you.
还是硬汉一条 兄弟
You look like a goddamn cold piece of steel, brother.
好了 哥们 帮我画完这只鸟
Yeah, well. Okay, my friend, let's finish this bird up.
快点吧 兄弟 几年了 才画了几个字母
Well, let's do it, bro. It's taken you a couple of years to do a couple of letters.
我们得开除 根拿
We had to get rid of Gunner.
他又发疯病了 不能再留了
Well, he went Crankenstein on your ass. You got to cut him loose.
你想入伙吗?
You wanna fill in?
老实说
Let me tell you something.
还记得我们上次在哪儿吗?
Remember where we was last time?
我们在哪?当时我们泡在泥血里
Where were we? We were ass-deep in that mud and blood.
- 尼日利亚 - 没错 你的手被打的一塌糊涂
- Nigeria. - Yeah, your hand was all shot to shit.
你血流成河 我也浑身挂彩
You were bleeding all over the place, and I was bleeding,
你知道 我干了件什么事吗? 我对自己说
and you know what I did? I promised myself,
我不想孤零零地 像个马蜂窝似的死在全是血的烂泥里
I don't wanna die all alone, full of holes in the mud and blood.
我要死得其所 我要和女人死在一起
I'm gonna die with something that counts. I'm gonna die with a woman.
我要和一个关心我的人死在一起
I wanna die with someone who cares about me, you know.
我不会为女人去死
I don't wanna die for a woman.
我只想死在女人身边 这就是我的愿望
I wanna die laying next to a woman. That's what I want.
- 这下热闹啦 - 没错 我从这里就能闻到他的味
- It's Christmastime. - Yeah, I can smell him from here.
克里斯莫斯 最近还好吗 兄弟?
Mr. Christmas. How you doing, brother?
很好 杜尔
I'm good, Tool.
太太好吗?
How's the missus?
很好
Yeah, all good.
那就好
Oh, good.
瞧瞧这个 你觉得怎么样?
So, take a look. What do you think?
看起来 还是像只黑乎乎的鸡
It still looks like a black chicken.
黑乎乎的鸡?
Black chicken?
哥们 见到你真好 兄弟
Man. It's good to see you, brother. Miss you.
今天晚上你看上没什么精神啊 怎么了
You're looking very beige tonight. What's up?
和平常一样
The usual.
- 一切都好 - 是的
- All good? - Yeah.
我有个好主意
I got a great idea.
让我为你画上两笔 画一个…
Why don't you let me doodle, like, a...
在你头上纹个蜘蛛网怎么样? 就纹在你的头顶
Charlotte's web on your head? On the top of your head.
来点花样 搞点气氛
You know, something different, something exciting.
因为你这个圆溜溜 肉绷绷的脑袋真是绝了
'Cause you got one of them perfectly-shaped domed, muscular heads.
我纹个蜘蛛网在你头顶
I could put a web on the top of the head.
也许再弄个怀了孕的蜘蛛精 从你耳朵里钻出来
Maybe a pregnant Charlotte coming out of your ear,
四下张望 不让虫子进来
peeking around, making sure them bugs don't come inside.
她的长腿悬在你的脖子上
Her long leg dangling down your neck.
- 性感 对吗? - 非常性感
- Yeah. Sexy, right? - Very sexy.
他看起来很激动
He looks thrilled.
告诉你 今晚我觉得运气不错
Well. Okay, I'll tell you what. I'm feeling a little lucky tonight.
我觉得很准
I'm feeling very accurate.
- 下次再说吧 - 别这样 打败他
- Another time. Come on. - Come on, take him on.
来吧 克里斯莫斯 出手吧 宝贝
Come on, Christmas. Bring it, baby.
别起哄 求你了
Don't encourage him, please.
他这辈子都别想打败你
He never beat you in your life.
来吧 克里斯莫斯 输刀不输人
Come on, Christmas, no disgrace in losing.
哪位?
Yes?
是
Yeah.
好
Okay.
我接了三个活
Well, I got three pieces of work.
其中两个小菜一碟 另一个龙潭虎穴
Two a walk in the park, and one to hell and back.
- 我想一个人静一段时间 - 振作 约对方出来
- I need some time alone. - Hey, cheer up. Make the meeting.
(瓦里拉岛)
老大
将军！叛徒抓回来了
你偷了我的东西
尊敬的阁下我从来没偷过你的东西
这块土地上没有任何东西属于你
所有的一切都是我的 明白吗
我以我孩子的性命发誓 我真的没偷
我明白 可我没法看透你
我怎么知道你说的是不是真话?
现在我们看清楚了
Now we can see inside of him.
他说谎
And I see lies.
他不是偷你的东西 是偷我们的东西
He wasn't stealing from you. He was stealing from us both.
你想让你的那些蠢货尊重你吗? 灭了这两个人
You want your apes' respect? Snuff those two.
不用拐弯抹角
Let's just keep it simple.
只要价钱好 我们不在乎在哪干活
If the money's right, we don't care where the job is.
- 明白吗? - 我们不用浪费时间
- Got it? - Let's quit jerking off,
谈生意吧 让我看看你想不想干
get down to business, see who's hungry.
我知道你的真名也许不叫巴尼·罗斯
I know your real name's probably not Barney Ross.
你也不必知道我的名字
You don't need to know my name.
你只要知道一件事 这份活是真的 钱也是真金白银
The only thing you need to know is the job's real and the money's real.
既然我们现在身处这种好地方
But since we're in this nice place,
你姑且就称我为教堂先生吧
you might as well just call me Mr. Church.
好的 教堂 我能为你做什么?
Okay, Church. What can I do for you?
稍等一会 我还在等一个人
In a minute. I'm still waiting for one more guy.
谁?
Who?
你认识他?
You know him?
是的 我们以前是一个小队的
Yeah, we used to be on the same team together.
我这个老不死的“好朋友”在这干什么?
What's my oldest, worst friend doing here?
你们两位都是我们的首选
Both of your names came to the top of the list.
- 有什么问题吗? - 是的
- Is that a problem? - Yeah.
我早该一枪干掉他
Should've shot him when I had the chance.
大个子巴尼·罗斯
Big Barney Ross.
胖子地老鼠
Bigger Trench mouse.
- 你在这干什么?让上帝赏口饭吃? - 也许
- What are you doing? Praying for work? - Could be.
最近身体不好吗?
Have you been sick?
- 你瘦了 - 是吗?
- You've lost weight. - Really?
我的肉倒全让你长去了 伙计
Whatever weight I lost, you found, pal.
你们不会想掏出鸡巴 互相搞一搞吧?
You guys aren't gonna start sucking each other's dicks, are you?
我们谈生意吧 看看谁想干这份活
Let's get down to business, see who wants the work.
你们听说过一个叫维林那的小岛吗?
You ever hear of an island called Vilena?
- 没有 - 我知道
- No. - Yeah.
海湾里的一个小岛
It's a little island in the Gulf.
没错
That's right.
- 你应该多学点文化 - 多谢提醒
- You should read more. - Thanks.
我的人对岛上的一些资源很感兴趣
There are resources on that island that my people are very interested in.
可一个叫加尔萨的将军推翻了临时政府
But a general by the name of Garza has overthrown the half-ass government.
没错
That's right.
我的人和这个叫加尔萨的政治狂人 发生了点小矛盾
My people are having a problem with this fanatic Garza.
- 你想让加尔萨滚蛋? - 我想让他死
- So you want Garza gone? - I want him dead.
只需要出动一支小部队就行了
All it takes is a little army.
只有白痴才会干这个活
Only an idiot would do this job.
- 多少钱? - 果然不出我所料
- How much? - Oh, like I said.
我很忙 这活给我这位朋友做吧
I'm busy anyway, so give this job to my friend here.
他超喜欢在丛林里打滚
He loves playing in the jungle.
- 我说的对吗? - 对
- Right? - Right.
找个时间一起吃个饭?
Hey, why don't we have dinner?
好啊 什么时候?
Sure. When?
- 等你死了以后 - 太快了
- In a thousand years. - Too soon.
- 他是不是他妈的有毛病? - 他想当总统
- What's his fucking problem? - He wants to be president.
首先 我得去岛上侦察一下
I got to recon this island first.
我会为你在岛上安排一个接头人
I'll have a contact for you on the island.
早走早好
Good riddance.
我猜没人敢接你这个活
I got a feeling everyone else has passed on this job,
我要500万美金
so our fee is $5 mil.
- 500万? - 先付一半
- $5 mil? - And I want half upfront,
另一半汇入海外账户
and the other half in an offshore account.
- 有问题吗? - 没有
- You got a problem with that? - No.
不过我很介意被人耍
What I have a problem with is people who try to fuck me over.
如果你拿了钱 却不干活
So if you take this money and you don't deliver,
我还有我的人
me and my people
会把你和你的人
are gonna come get you and your people
剁成一块一块的去喂狗
and chop you up into little fucking dog treats.
听懂了吗?
You got a problem with that?
谈谈细节吧
Let's talk.
不管是谁臭了你 看来都很糟
Whoever stood you up sounds bad.
是啊 不过报酬很不错
Yeah, but it will pay good.
嗯 先不谈钱 你的准则是怎么回事?
Yeah, well, money aside. What happened to your code?
什么准则
What code's that?
“目标必须值得去做”
"The target has to deserve it."
兴趣不足 已经作废了
That was canceled due to lack of interest.
- 你真黑 又黑又冷 - 被你发现了
- You're dark. Dark and cold. - You noticed.
- 顺便说一下 我可不吃这一套 - 你会的
- And I ain't buying into that, by the way. - You will.
去附近转转吧 年轻人
Stick around, young man, you will.
维林那
Vilena.
又有新活了吗?
Next job?
是要去那吗?
They got work there?
别这样
Come on.
你不该来这 根拿
You know you shouldn't be here, Gunner.
别扔下我
Don't replace me.
我能行
I'm good.
我还能行
I'm still good.
你还在吸毒
You're still using.
我没法再相信你 哥们
I can't trust you anymore, man.
- 你不相信我? - 是
- You can't trust me? - Hmm.
你不相信我?
You can't trust me?
是的
I can't.
你不相信我?
You can't trust me?
你小心点
Be careful.
你在威胁我吗 根拿?
You threatening me, Gunner?
没有 我心肠好着呢
Nah, I'm a nice guy.
根据这个叫教堂的家伙给我的资料
So, going over the info this guy Church gave me,
这个岛大约有6000人
there's probably about 6,000 people on the island.
有多少士兵?
How many soldiers?
大概几百个
Maybe a couple of hundred.
几百个士兵足以控制这个小地方
It wouldn't take much more than that to control a space that small.
你真明白
You do know that.
太好了 他们是一支小型部队
Great, they've got a small army.
我们呢?
What do we got?
只有四个半人
Four and a half men.
真令人作呕
That smells disgusting.
作呕? 我的鸡肉秋葵汤坏了?
Disgusting? Chicken gumbo is bad,
不过老鼠和猩猩奶头吃起来很美味?
but eating on rats and gorilla nipples, that's delicious?
一点也不好笑
Not so funny.
- 我要加工资 - 为什么?
- I need a raise. - Why?
我要为我儿子多存点钱
I need more money for my son.
我要送他上好学校
I want to send him to a better school.
- 阴阳什么时候成的家? - 不知道
- Did Yin Yang get a family? - I have no idea.
你们没问 我废什么话
You don't ask, I don't tell.
好了 还是像以前那样分成
Anyway, the pay share stays the same.
以后也一样
That's the way it's gonna be.
目标人物是加尔萨将军
Now the target on this island is a guy named General Garza.
- 他犯了什么事? - 谁管他犯了什么事?
- What's the problem? - Who gives a shit what the problem is?
我们自己的麻烦就够多了
We got enough problems right here of our own.
这些问题不解决 我们都完蛋
We don't get rid of those first, they're gonna get rid of us.
托尔·鲁德 你什么时候看的医生?
Toll Road, when was the last time you saw your analyst?
- 今天早上 - 是吗?医生怎么说的?
- This morning. - Yeah? What'd you talk about?
逃避型人格障碍
Avoidant personality disorder.
你想得太多了
You think too much.
托尔·鲁德 你不是一般人
You know, Toll Road, you're a great guy, a little fucked up, no doubt about it,
所以 一定会有不一般的问题 知道吗?
and you're always gonna have unusual problems, right?
- 是的 - 你在说我的耳朵?
- Yeah. - You're talking about my ear.
又来了 别再说你的耳朵了
Come on. Don't start with the ear again.
- 别再说你耳朵上的那点事了 - 别再说耳朵了
- Not the ear story. - The ear story, not again.
- 我们都听过 - 我们不想再听了
- We all know the ear story. - We don't want to hear the ear story.
- 你们都知道我在大学摔过跤 - 没错
- We all know I wrestled in college. - Right.
摔跤运动员的耳朵通常会有血块
A common injury associated with that sport is trauma to the ear, a clot.
如果不管它 会导致耳软骨萎缩
Which, if left unattended, causes a contraction in the cartilage
变成开花耳
and forms cauliflower ears.
我的室友总是没完没了地 说起我耳朵的形状
My college roommate used to bring up my ear configuration all the time.
不管是在聚会 还是社交
Parties, social events, you name it.
其实我倒真不太在意他说这些 因为他经常吹捧我
That didn't really bother me all that much because he's usually bragging about
说我的耳朵是勇气的象征
how my ears are a badge of courage.
- 让我都有些不好意思 - 当然了
- Made me a little less self-conscious. - Of course it would.
但这一切很快就结束了
But that was short-lived.
春假里的一天早上 我听到他在背着我打电话
One morning, during spring break, I hear him on the phone, bagging on me,
说到了我“怪异的耳朵”
talking about my "queer ear."
有什么可笑的吗?
You see something funny?
抱歉 你继续
Sorry, go ahead.
我这才意识到仅仅是外表上的不同 我就已经变成了一个笑柄
So I realize I'd become the brunt of a joke simply because I look a little bit different.
所以我决定教训一下我的室友
So I decided to educate my roommate
对于外表有所不同的人 应该给予正常的礼貌
on the common decency that should be afforded people who look a little different.
我猛撞他的臭脑袋
I smashed him upside his goddamn head!
…一下又一下
Several times.
直到他的脑袋开花
Until he had a little cluster of cauliflower all his own.
- 你想说什么? - 病人不容易
- And your point is? - It ain't easy being green.
你们以为我他妈的在说什么?
The fuck you think I'm talking about?
好了 我和克里斯莫斯会去一趟维林那
Anyway, me and Christmas are gonna head down to Vilena
探探岛上的情况 看看这活能不能接
and scout the island to see if we should take the job.
对方付我们多少钱?我需要钱养家
How much we get paid? I need more money for my family.
养什么家?
What fucking family are you talking about?
我家
My family.
你知道 别问
You know, don't ask.
听着 那女孩不适合你
Listen, that girl wasn't your type.
是她没福气
Her loss, right?
我应该敲碎那混蛋的下巴
I should have broke that bastard's jaw.
你也许逃过一劫 被敲碎下巴的人可能是你
Maybe you were lucky. He could have broke yours.
- 不可能 - 克里斯莫斯 我理解你
- Impossible. - You know, Christmas, I understand,
一时的相处
but let's just say you were with her for a couple of hours,
或许很甜蜜 很刺激也很情意绵绵
and it's nice, and it's hot and heavy,
可之后呢 会怎么样?
but after that, think about it.
接下来你要干什么呢?
What do you do for the rest of the day?
也许分手对你是件好事
She probably did you a favor.
现在你可以多留点时间给自己了
Now you have more time to feel sorry for yourself.
你真是个冷血混蛋
You're a bleak bastard.
早上好 早上好
Morning. Morning.
早上好！会说英语吗?
Morning! Speak English?
好大的飞机啊
Big plane, huh?
没错 我们用它运送受伤的动物
Yeah, we use it to transport injured animals.
- 为什么到这来? - 我们是鸟类学家
- Why are you here? - Ornithologists.
到这里拍些珍稀鸟类
We're photographing exotic birds.
你很紧张吗?
You're nervous?
紧张?
Nervous?
没有啊 为什么这么说?
No. Why?
你看起来很紧张
You just look nervous.
我不紧张 我紧张吗?
I'm not nervous. Do I look nervous?
你的皮肤有点干
Your skin looks a little dry.
一定是飞的太高了
That's because of the altitude.
不是因为太高了 你开飞机的时候 应该把窗子关上
Well, it's not the altitude. You fly with the window open all the time.
- 脱水 - 对 是脱水
- Dehydration. - Yeah, it is dehydration.
不过还是有办法解决的 干细胞什么的 换新皮肤
But there's ways to get around that. There's new skin, it's like stem cell research.
你看上去很帅 不用担心
You are looking handsome. Don't worry about it.
- 你嫉妒了? - 有一点
- You're jealous? - I'm a little jealous. Yeah.
你还年轻 风华正茂啊
You're younger. You have youth on your side.
总的来说 我还是喜欢我现在这样子 你呢
Overall, I'm happy to be myself. Are you?
- 你说完了 - 说完了
- So you're done. - Done.
- 很高兴认识你 - 很高兴认识你
- Good to know you. - Good to know you.
我们一直这样
Yeah, we do this all the time.
互相开玩笑 这样在飞行当中能保持清醒
We kid ourselves. That's how we stay awake on the plane.
我可是飞机上唯一清醒的
I'm the only one who stays awake on the plane.
- 他总是睡觉 - 说得对
- He's always sleeping. - Yeah, you're right.
- 地址在哪? - 在我脑子里
- What's the address? - Yeah, it's in my head.
能告诉我吗?
Do you wanna share it?
凯莱酒吧
It's the Gloria Cantina.
用西班牙语说 应该是酒吧凯莱
So actually, Cantina Gloria in Spanish.
西班牙语 你以为你是谁 佐罗?
Spanish. Who are you, Zorro?
军人
Army.
- 该死 - 快走
- Shit. - Come on.
这边
In there.
- 在拍吗? - 拍了
- You rolling? - No, I'm on holiday.
你 你 把卡车挪开！
You, you, move the truck!
拍那个穿西装的 来个特写
Get the suit. Tighten up on the suit.
拍好了
Got him.
看看这些小丑 一群莽夫
Look at these clowns, hand-picked monkeys.
看得出有什么不对劲吗?
What's wrong with this picture?
所有的事都不对
Everything.
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
不 问题就在这
No, that's the point, you know.
你以为很了解一个人 可事实上不是
You think you know someone, and you truly do not.
你不是说过:“没有女人也能过的男人”
Aren't you the guy who said, "The man who best gets along with women...
“才是最会与女人相处的”吗?
...is the man who can get along without them"?
不对 不对 你没认真听
No, no. You're so not listening.
我说的是如果你被女人控制住了
I'm talking about when you give all the control to the woman.
- 你就失去了主动权 - 对
- You relinquish the power. - Right.
- 姑娘获得了主动 - 对
- You give it all to the girl. - Right.
真到了那时候 她会挖出你的心
Right at that very moment is the time that she will tear out your heart.
再去和送奶工滚床单 最后怀上陌生人的孩子
She'll screw the milkman, she'll get pregnant with a stranger.
我告诉你 真的会这样
I'm telling you, it's exactly what's happening
而且每次交新女朋友都会重复发生
and it's repeating itself every relationship I have.
一模一样
It's the same.
事实上 她不适合你
Truthfully, she wasn't your type.
- 这事没完 - 好好享受一下单身生活吧
- Well, I wasn't finished. - Look, enjoy your freedom.
- 迟早也轮到你 - 好
- Yeah, you wait till it happens to you. - It has.
两位想喝点什么?
不用 谢谢
接头人来迟了
Contact's late.
我们走吧
All right, let's go.
别急
Chill.
这个干果长腿了
One of the nuts has legs.
我讨厌这身衣服 我讨厌这帽子
I hate this outfit. I hate this hat.
摘下来
Take it off.
你被女人甩过吗?
Have you ever been rejected?
如果我死了你会伤心吗?
Would you be sad if I was dead?
你再说 我就要发火了 知道吗?
You're really pushing the boundaries of our relationship, you know that?
- 那个是接头人吗? - 可能是
- Is that the contact? - Could be.
她长的真一般
Too bad she's so homely.
别走神
Stay focused.
你是接头人吗?
Are you the contact?
我叫桑德拉
I'm Sandra.
你们叫什么?
What are your names?
布达 佩斯
Buda, Pest.
请跟我来
Follow me, please.
布达和佩斯?好极了
Buda and Pest? Nice.
这些都是你画的吗?
Did you do all these?
是的 送你一幅
Yes. Take one.
算是礼物
A gift.
无功不受禄
I don't take free gifts.
- 这张多少钱? - 不收钱
- How much you want for it? - Nothing.
送人礼物不能收钱
Taking money for something is not a gift.
不收任何回报才叫礼物
Taking nothing for something is.
这里一直像这样吗?
Is it like this all the time?
过去这里是个美丽的地方
This place was a beautiful place.
后来 来了一伙有钱人 加尔萨将军就把自己出卖了
Then one day, they came with money, and General Garza sold his soul.
不服从的人全被杀了
And people who fight back are killed.
你说来了一伙人
You said "they" came with money.
他们什么来头?
Who's "they"?
我只知道他们是美国人
Some Americans. That's all I know.
不过 总有一天一切都会恢复原样
But someday all of this will change back.
你真的这么想吗?
You really believe that?
是的
Yes.
你家里还有些什么人 桑德拉?
You have a family, Sandra?
我妈妈在我很小的时候就死了
My mother, when I was little, she died.
我爸爸 也死了
And my father, he's gone, too.
你呢?
Do you?
- 我? - 对
- Me? - Yes.
他有一辆卡车和一架水上飞机
He has a truck and a seaplane.
桑德拉 能尽可能靠近宫殿吗?
Sandra, how close can you get to the palace?
宫殿?干什么?
The palace? Why?
我们想看看风景
We just wanna check out the view.
那里没风景可看
There is no view.
不管怎么说 带我们去一趟吧?
Why don't we just go there anyway, okay?
我要的收成在哪?
Where is my grove?
你的工人在哪?
Where is your manpower?
你知道古柯叶要多久才有收成吗?
Do you know how long it takes for a coca field to produce?
你当然不知道 让我告诉你
Of course you don't. Let me tell you.
我们比预计的迟了八个星期
We are eight weeks behind schedule.
给你的农民吃点苦头 把我的东西快点种出来
Kick your peasants' asses. Get me my product.
你在我的人面前 用这种口气和我说话 很不好
When you talk like this to me in front of my men, it's no good.
你们靠我吃饭
I am your lifeline.
靠我平息了动乱
I am the one who coordinates all this confusion.
我在给你财路
I am making you rich.
有钱是件好事
And being wealthy is very good.
钱可以让人肆无忌惮 随心所欲
It allows people to be the real asswipes nature intended them to be.
有些东西钱买不来
Sometimes things are just not worth the money.
金钱是万能的
Sure they are.
桑德拉 我想问问你
Sandra, I was wondering about something you were saying.
- 从女性的观点来看… - 你在干什么?
- From a female point of view... - What are you doing?
谈话 找出答案 完全出于好奇
Conversing. Look it up. Out of curiosity,
你经历过你喜欢的人冒犯你吗?
you ever have a person you liked disrespect you in a bad way?
冒…
Dis...
我不知道怎么用西班牙语说“冒犯”
I'm not sure what the Spanish is for "disrespect."
又来了 天啊 你怎么还不能振作起来
Come on. Why don't you man up? Jesus!
她不适合你
She wasn't your type.
你再说一遍“她不适合我”
Why don't you just keep saying, "She wasn't my type?"
我就一枪崩开你空空的脑袋
So I could put a bullet in your bleak brain!
看看我在和谁说话 吸血鬼的生活导师
Look who I'm talking to. Dracula's life coach.
难怪你现在还是单身
No wonder you're alone.
桑德拉 快到了吗?
Sandra, are we close?
就在那里
It's just over there.
- 请把车停下 - 对
- Pull over, please. - Yeah, really.
- 他要去哪儿? - 我很高兴你这么问
- Where is he going? - I'm glad you asked.
这么说吧
Well, I suppose you could say
我喜欢以不同的角度看世界
we like to look at the world from different views.
至于你…狼心狗肺
You... You got a black heart.
她不适合你
She wasn't your type.
我们上路吧
We should get going.
他这个人情绪波动很大
He's very emotional.
你们在找什么?
What are you looking for?
桑德拉 你有没有给我们下套?
Sandra, how do I know you're not setting us up?
我连“下套”是什么意思都不知道
What does "setting us up" mean?
你不像干这行的人
You don't look like the kind of person that we deal with all the time.
你为什么干这行?
How did you get involved in this?
来过一个美国人
An American came here.
他让我朋友带你们四处转转 我朋友害怕了 所以让我代替他
He asked my friend to show you around. He was afraid, so he asked me to.
你不害怕吗?
And you're not afraid?
我也害怕
I'm afraid.
可他说你们也许能帮我们
But he said maybe you can help Vilena.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
为什么?
Why not?
要想让这地方走回正轨
To get this place going again,
必须把现有的一切都推倒重来
you have to rip the guts out of it and start from the ground up
我可不觉得值得这么做
and even I don't think that's worth the money,
听我说 如果我是你 我就赶紧走
so if I were you, I'd leave. Just leave.
该走应该是你
You should leave.
别开口 我来说
Don't say anything. Let me talk.
站住
不许动
他在这干什么?
告诉过你不许到这儿来
为什么?
维林那不是你们的
我们警告过你
就算是将军的女儿也一样可以格杀勿论
你们没有权利管我
带她见她父亲
你是谁
快跑！
Run!
- 去救她 - 好的
- Get her. - Got it.
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
- 差点把我干掉！ - 不用客气
- You could have killed me! - You're welcome.
什么?
What?
开快点 我们来了
All right, speed it up. We're on the way.
如果我们能逃出去 就是奇迹了
If we get out of here, it's a miracle.
- 她和我们一起走 是吗? - 最好是
- She's coming with us, right? - She'd better.
- 我们怎么离开这里? - 我们有一架飞机
- How can we leave? - We got a plane.
- 不 我不能离开 - 一定得走 你没得选
- No, I can't leave. - Yeah, well, you don't have a choice.
- 不 我不走 - 什么?他们一个小时就能找到你
- Yes, I do. - Yeah? They'll find you in an hour.
- 也许吧 但我还是选择留下 - 留下干什么?这里没什么可留恋的
- Maybe, but I'm staying. - Staying for what? There's nothing here.
我有
Not to you.
听着 如果你留下 必死无疑 她和我们一起走
Look, if you stay, then you're dead. She's leaving with us.
- 里面的人我来处理 - 帮我拖住他们一分钟
- I got the guys inside. - Give me a 60-second lead.
- 明白 走 走 走！ - 快来
- You got it. Go, go, go! - Come on.
进去
Get in.
- 进去 - 不
- Get in. - No.
- 进去 - 不 不 我不能走
- Get in. - No, no, I can't.
- 我们快走 - 我不能走 我的家在这里
- Let's go. - I can't. I belong here.
- 没时间了 - 走 你快走
- There's no time. - Go, you go.
求你 快走吧
Please, go.
该死！
Shit.
嗨
Hey!
你看起来很紧张
You look nervous.
快点！
Come on!
快跑 你个混球！
Run, you bastard!
- 那女孩呢? - 走了 她不愿离开
- Where's the girl? - Gone. She wouldn't leave.
不愿离开?
Wouldn't leave?
谁愿待在这种鬼地方?
Why the hell would anybody wanna stay?
去她的
The hell...
The hell with it.
- 飞吧 宝贝 飞吧 - 快点 宝贝
- Climb, baby, climb. - Come on, baby.
该死的
God damn it.
- 回去? - 是的
- Going back? - Yeah.
- 送他们下油锅 - 送他们下油锅 干吧
- Fry and die. - Fry and die. Let's do it.
他们想干什么?
What are they doing?
爽！
Yes!
干的好
Great job.
我们下了战书
That was a statement!
两个职业杀手怎么可能通过安检
How did two obvious professionals pass right through security personnel,
杀了41个士兵 然后逃走的呢?
kill 41 soldiers and get away?
有人协助 肯定是这样
With help, that's how.
所有的事都控制在我们手里 除了一个人
Everything's under control, except one detail,
一个想让自己的老爸和公司 一起完蛋的好女儿
a daughter who wants her father and company dead and gone.
真是家门不幸
Bad Shakespeare.
我的手下已经去抓她了
Somehow the company parasites got to her.
她是你女儿 我很遗憾
Look, she's your daughter, and that's tragic.
可是 无论如何 她都得死
But blood or not, she goes.
这就是做生意的代价
Call it the price of doing business.
虎毒不食子
You don't kill your familia.
过年过节怕寂寞的话 就到我家来 哥们
Come around my house during the holidays, pal.
鸟不错
Nice bird.
首先 和一个拿枪大汉谈生意
First of all, I don't feel comfortable
我觉得很不舒服
talking business with a giant carrying a shotgun.
这位帅哥不肯交枪
Pretty boy wouldn't give it up.
除非你们不想找他们
Not if you wanna know where they are.
你知道些什么?
What do you know?
我以前和他们是一伙的
I used to be one of them.
为什么你要背叛他们
Why are you turning on them?
意见不合
Lovers' quarrel.
我给你5万
We settle on 50.
不成 精明人
No, math whiz.
我要10万 预付
We settle on 100 grand, upfront, in my pocket.
这家伙想犯混啊
The guy thinks he's a real badass.
其实 我在做恐怖秀
Actually, I'm a horror show.
这老家伙真他妈搞笑
This geezer's a bloody joke.
生活就是一个玩笑 蠢货！
Life's a joke, gum-chew.
我在一个屁大的地方站了 整整六个小时
I've been standing in a space about the size of your mouth for six hours.
如果不想让我把你的丑脸 打个稀巴烂
If you don't want that Fu Manchu knocked back into the '60s,
就给我闭上这张臭嘴 放尊重点！
you'd better keep your gum-chewing trap shut and show some respect!
嗨
Hey.
想整容吗 帅哥?
Need a facelift, pretty boy?
拿过来
Bring it.
住手 潘恩
Back off, Paine.
老子要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
我们需要他
We need him.
住手！
Back off!
我想事情大概是这样的
Here's what I think is happening.
这个自称教堂的家伙 是中央情报局的一个头头
This guy who calls himself Church is really a front for the CIA.
这么说 我们在为中央情报局干活?
So we're working for the agency?
是的 教堂雇我们去干掉将军
Yeah. Church hired us to take out the General,
但真正的目标是这个人
James Munroe but the real target's this guy, James Munroe.
他以前也是中央情报局特工 之后财迷心窍
He used to be with the agency, but got greedy,
背叛了情报局 并和将军结成了团伙
went rogue and teamed up with the General
控制了毒品生意
to keep the whole drug operation for themselves.
这么一来情报局损失巨大
And that's a big cash loss.
但教堂和情报局不敢让海豹突击队
But Church and the agency can't afford to send in the Navy SEALs
或者特种部队去收拾自己人
or the Special Forces to take out one of their own.
这样影响非常不好 所以他们就雇了我们去杀他
That'd be a bad headline, so they hire us to kill him.
然后他们重新掌握毒品生意
And they're back in business.
- 再把我们干掉 - 神不知鬼不觉
- And we're taken out. - Nobody's gonna miss us.
- 是不是出价500万? - 你有钱也没命花
- Is it still $5 million? - You'd never live to spend it.
我要通知教堂交易取消
I'm telling Church the deal's off.
你们觉得怎么样?
Sound about right?
就这么办
That's about right.
我同意
I agree.
你的头盔还在吗?
You still got the helmet?
他在哪?
Where is he?
- 那是谁? - 小混混
- Who the hell is that? - Some punk.
- 别管他 - 有我们呢
- Don't worry about it. - We got your back.
他敢过来 我们就让他满地找牙
If he comes over here, we'll bust his ass.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
要你的命
Your life.
我早就想这么做
I was thinking about taking it.
是吗?
Is that right?
可我在小房子里会很不舒服 所以进号子有点讨厌
But I don't do so well in tight spaces, so going to prison worries me.
你不该打她的脸
You shouldn't have bruised her face.
打了又怎么样?
Really?
我喜欢她的脸
I would have liked to have kept it the way it was.
这婊子你留着吧 老子已玩腻了
Keep the bitch, 'cause I'm done with it.
李
Lee.
下一次 我让你做不成男人 朋友
Next time, I'll deflate all your balls, friend.
现在你该知道我是干什么的吧
Now you know what I do for a living.
我不完美 但你应该等我
I'm not perfect, but you should have waited.
我值得你等
I was worth it.
她在哪儿?
Where is she?
你女儿也会画画?
So your daughter paints, too?
都是理想惹的祸！
This is how it starts!
我们走 这里什么也没有
There's nothing here. Let's go.
一切都结束了！
Or how it ends!
怎么了 巴尼?你从不睡觉吗?
What's the matter, Barney? Don't you ever sleep?
不睡 你的女朋友呢?
No. What happened to your girlfriend?
又吹了一个 兄弟
Another one bites the dust, brother.
我本来要为她纹这个 你猜怎么? 我会继续画完
I was gonna paint this for her, and you know what? I'm gonna finish it.
然后 把它砸个稀巴烂
Then I'm just gonna smash the shit out of it.
你想一个人待着吗?
You wanna be alone?
不需要 有心事?
Not really. So, what's up?
在岛上 遇见了一个女孩
On this island, there was this girl.
很平常啊
There usually are.
她是我们的向导 也是目标人物的女儿
You know, she showed us around. She was the target's daughter.
她本来可以和我们一起走 可她不走
And when she had a chance to leave, she didn't do it.
很勇敢
She had some guts.
可我为什么老是想着她?
Why can't I get that out of my mind?
她代表着一些东西
You know, she stands for something.
哥们 我们的人生空无一物
You know, man, we don't stand for shit.
曾经有过 可都被生活磨掉了 就像这幅画
We used to, but that dried all up, like this is gonna dry all up.
慢慢地干掉
This here paint is gonna dry.
我们没了什么?
What dried up?
没了信仰 哥们 失去对灵魂的信仰
Just belief, man. Just the belief in the soul,
我不知道怎么说 人性 兄弟
just, I don't know, the human parts, brother.
还记得我们那次在波斯尼亚吗?
You remember that time we was up in Bosnia?
我们干掉了那伙塞尔维亚混蛋
We took down them Serb bad boys.
我们的弟兄都被砍死在我们身边
All our guys were getting chopped up all around us,
血流成河
and there was blood everywhere.
我从没想过能活着离开那里
I never thought I was gonna make it out of there,
- 我知道你也没想过 - 是的
- and I know you didn't, either. - Yeah.
觉得自己已经死了
Kind of feeling like dead, too, you know?
我陷入了一片黑暗之中
My head's all a very black place.
我失去了信仰
I don't believe in shit.
只有该死的血一样的黑暗
Just goddamn Dracula black.
我记得我喝了一瓶当地的烈性酒 梅子白兰地
I remember I got this bottle of the local shit they have over there, that Slivovitz.
我记不清了 好像是叫这个名字
I don't know, I think that's what it was called.
我感觉不痛了
And I ain't feeling no pain now.
之后 我上了…
And I'd come up on this...
我上了一座老木桥 我看见…
I'd come up on this old wooden bridge, and I see this...
我看见…
I see this...
我看见一个女人站在那 她…
I see this woman standing there, you know? And she's...
我走了过去 她看见了我
I stepped out, and she saw me,
直勾勾地看着我 我也看着她
and she's just looking right in my eyes, and I was looking right in her eyes.
我知道她想干什么
I knew what she was gonna do.
她看着我 我知道她想跳下去
She looked at me, and I knew she was gonna jump.
你知道我干了什么吗?
You know what I did, man?
我转过身 离开了 之后就听见落水声
I just turned around and I kept walking, until I heard that splash.
她就这么死了
Then she was gone.
在那儿 杀了那么多人
And after taking all them lives,
终于有机会救一个人的时候 我却没救
here was one that I could have saved, but I didn't.
后来我意识到
And what I realized later on was,
如果我当时救了那个女人 我也许…
if I had saved that woman, I might have,
也许就能留下一些人性
I don't know, saved what was left of my soul, you know?
桑德拉
Sandra,
是阿历克斯桑德拉的简称 拉丁语的意思是“人类的守护者”
short for Alexsandra, which is Latin for "Defender of mankind,"
没错 你就是
And, bingo, here you are.
人如其名
Now that's synergy.
你听不懂
You're not following that.
我知道你可能也不懂 毕竟你们国家里98%都是文盲
And I know you're probably not, illiteracy being 98% in your country.
试试看吧
Try following this.
一个很有智慧的故人曾经告诉过我 真正的男人绝不打女人
A very wise dead man once told me that a real man never strikes a woman.
最多吓吓她们 但绝不动手
You push some if you have to, but you never strike them.
可是 这个人却没有那种善心
This man, however, does not share that moral dilemma.
告诉我 桑德拉 美国人为什么到这来?
So the question, Sandra, why were the Americans here?
笨蛋
你为什么不跟他们走?
你杀了那么多人
为什么不把我也杀了?
把我也杀了啊
你杀了那么多人 干嘛不把我也杀了
你这个凶手！
放开我 放开我
让我出去 快让我出去
让我出去 放开我
你们这些混蛋
放开我 你们这些混蛋
别反抗
Don't fight back.
别怕
Just relax.
再问一次 美国人对你说了什么?
Again, what did the Americans tell you?
他们在查谁?
Who were they after?
继续
Continue.
你想要答案
You wanted answers.
不是这样！
Not like that!
你说什么都行
Whatever you say.
- 我要回维林那 - 真的吗?事情有变化?
- I'm going back to Vilena. - Yeah? Something change?
- 有什么计划? - 没有计划
- What's the plan? - There is no plan.
- 等等 等等 我们得筹划一下 - 我一个去 你们不用去
- Wait, wait, wait. We need a strategy. - I'm going. You're not.
- 什么? - 我说了我一个去 你们不用去
- What? - I said I'm going. You guys aren't.
- 你干什么 是不是疯了? - 这是我一个人的事
- What are you, out of your mind? - It's personal business.
- 你不欠那个女人什么 - 我没说我欠她
- You don't owe that woman nothing. - I didn't say I did.
你想自杀吗?去吧 随你的便
You want to kill yourself? Go ahead, fine. Your call.
听着 我不想自杀 你们多保重 我必须去
Listen, I don't want to kill myself. You guys, take care. I got to do this.
- 嘿 嘿 嘿 - 干嘛?
- Hey, hey, hey. - What?
你不能这样对我们 让我们内疚
Don't lay this guilt crap on us. We don't deserve it.
这是我的选择 不需要内疚 不需要 保重
This is my choice. There's no guilt. There's no guilt. Take care.
他妈的 他自己选的
Yeah, fuck it. His choice. Yeah.
我说过我一个人去
I said I'm going alone.
我也去
I'm going, too.
阴阳 别闹 快滚出去
Come on, Yang, get the hell out.
开车吧
Just drive.
别害怕
Don't lose your nerve.
给我闭嘴 人渣
Don't talk to me, cockroach.
你为什么要这么做?
So, why are you doing this?
要死一起死
Friends die together.
把我的幸运戒指还我 快点
Hey. Give me the good luck ring. Come on.
别让我发火 阴阳 给我
Don't make me hurt you, Yang. Come on.
- 速度比幸运更重要 - 随便你怎么说
- Speed better than luck. - Whatever.
不容易
It's difficult.
你说什么?
What is?
我过的不容易 我需要更多钱
My life is difficult. I need more money.
为什么这么说?
Why is that?
- 我比别人工作更努力 - 别人和你一样努力
- I work harder than the rest. - No, you don't.
我比别人努力 因为他们比我高 做任何事我都得多出力
Yes, I do. Because they're taller, everything is harder for me.
受伤后 伤口看起来都比别人的大 因为我个子小
When I get hurt, the wound is bigger because I'm smaller.
走路 我得比别人多走几步
When I travel, I need to go farther.
我知道了 因为你个子小 对不对?
I know, 'cause you're smaller, right?
没错
Yes.
我活的比你想像的要难
My life is harder than you think.
- 我需要更多钱 - 我知道了 你说过
- I need more money. - I know. You told me.
要养家 是吗?
For your family, right?
我没有家
I don't have family.
我知道
I know.
也许将来会有
Maybe one day I will.
趴下！
Down!
- 你去外面！ - 为什么让我去?
- Get out there! - Why me?
因为你个子小
Because you're smaller.
再这么干 老子灭了你！
Do that again, I'll kill you!
根拿！
Gunner!
来吧 根拿
Come on, Gunner.
身手不错
Man's good.
你在干什么?你死定了 粉虫！
What are you doing? You're dead, junkie!
贱
Insect.
跳！
Bail!
该死！
Shit!
阴阳！
Yang!
出来 出来 不管你在哪儿！
Come out, come out, wherever you are!
结束了
It's over!
我们谈谈吧 我原谅你了 阴阳
Let's talk about this. I forgive you, Yang!
差点伤了我
That almost hurt.
住手！
Back off!
你穿多大号的鞋 三号? 打我啊 大脚
What do you wear, size three? Bring it, happy feet.
轮到我了！
Come on, bring it!
鞋号我说对了
Size matters.
根拿！
Gunner!
运气不错
Hello, karma!
该死的！
Shit!
你对我开枪
You shot me.
不怪我 你想杀他
Hey, don't say that. You were gonna kill him.
我只想吓吓他
No, I was just gonna scare him.
别装了 你从来没喜欢过他 你想杀他
Don't say that. You never liked him. You were gonna kill him.
是真的
That's true.
我会死吗
Am I dying?
这一枪差点打中心脏
The shot's a couple of inches above your heart.
根拿 是谁派你来的? 谁雇的你?
Gunner, who sent you? Who hired you?
现在还有关系吗?
Who cares?
就当帮我一个忙
Who cares? I care.
别犯混了 你这辈子够混了 就随和一次吧
Don't go out a total asshole. For once, cooperate.
是谁派你来的?谁雇的你? 告诉我 让我挽回局面
Who sent you? Who hired you? Tell me. Let me make it right.
好好安葬我
Bury me right.
我想要一个维京式葬礼
And I want a Viking funeral.
你是说把你放到一条船里 然后火葬?
You mean where they put you in a boat and set you on fire, Viking?
- 太对了 - 你不是维京人
- That's right! - You're not a Viking.
那又怎么样?没关系
So what? Who cares?
我答应你
If that's what you want, you got it.
谁派你来的?是谁? 那个女孩还活着吗?
Who sent you? Is the girl still alive?
靠近点
Come closer.
做你朋友真不容易
You know, it's not easy being your friend.
没错
That's true.
哥们 要死一起死 只要别让我们死两次
Man, we'll die with you. Just don't ask us to do it twice.
我想了个计划 路上详谈
I know the layout. I'll tell you about it on the way.
你又怎么了?
What the hell happened to you?
说来气人 不说了
It's too sad to talk about it.
我们上路
Let's fly.
敌人其实很害怕噪音
You know, the enemy's always been terrified of noise,
特别是枪声
especially shotguns.
这家伙一分钟能喷250发子弹
With this big boy spitting out 250 rounds a minute,
你说说看 谁能不害怕
you tell me who's tolerating that.
我信任你
You know what? I trust you.
见见我的女朋友
I want you to meet my girlfriend.
欧米亚·凯波姆
Omya Kaboom.
子弹发射以后
When Omya's prime is struck,
她会释放出一个加强小弹头
she gets off a miniature warhead that arms itself.
这个时候 任何挡在她前面的东西
And when that happens, anything that gets in my lady's way
都会被炸成一团肉泥
becomes instant red sauce and Jell-O.
如果还不够
And if that doesn't work,
她的妹妹随后就到
her sister will.
我再理一遍 根拿想杀你 你开枪杀了他
So let me get this right. Gunner tries to kill you, you shoot him
临死以前 他对你坦白了敌人的计划?
and, at death's door, he gives you the whole layout?
差不多
Something like that.
但我答应他要安排一个维京式葬礼
But I had to promise him this Viking funeral.
你必须把骨灰撒到大海里
You know, where you have to spread the ashes over the ocean.
那大概会毒死一千条鲸
What a way to poison about a thousand whales.
至少一千
At least.
听着 我们都得去给这个混蛋送行
Listen, we owe the big bastard a send-off.
- 我可以打赢他 - 我知道你能打赢他
- I would have win. - I know you would have win.
至少一百万条鲸
More like a million whales.
现在是3点36分 我们有20分钟的时间扫平这个地方
It's 3:36. We have 20 minutes to take this place down.
地下室交给我
I'll take the cellar.
有人来了
We've got company.
交给我 你们快走
I got him. You guys take off.
能告诉我为什么我训练出来的士兵
Is there a reason you've taken the soldiers this man has trained
被你弄得像白痴一样吗?
and made them look like fools?
他们是真正的战士
They look like warriors.
忠于我的战士
Warriors loyal to me.
我本以为是本地人 找了这些雇佣军来杀我
I thought the people of Vilena hired these mercenaries to kill me.
但我转念一想 也许是你安排的 因为你控制不了我
But then I think maybe this is your plan, because you cannot control me.
所以你严刑拷打桑德拉
And torturing Sandra works for you.
你想杀了她 让我难过
You want to kill her to make me suffer.
只要是人 就绝不会对孩子下毒手
A man can never kill a child.
除了你
But you can.
你疯了
You're losing your mind.
你控制不了我！
You do not control me!
把桑德拉带来
Bring Sandra here.
马上把她带来 不然我杀了你
Bring her now or I will kill you.
把她带来
Go get her.
你确定她不会认出我们吗
她看不见 放心玩
再说 这个婊子早晚得死
死到临头了  跟我们乐一乐吧
快来吧
你就别叫了 没人能听见
别碰我 你们这些禽兽
看来得给你点儿厉害
- 不要 不要 - 桑德拉 桑德拉 是我 桑德拉
- No, no. - Sandra, Sandra, it's me. Sandra.
是我 是我 桑德拉 是我
Hey, it's me, it's me. Sandra, it's me.
是我 是我 别害怕
It's me. It's me. It's okay.
没人会伤害你 知道吗?
Nobody's gonna hurt you, all right?
你为什么会在这里?
How are you here?
不为什么
I just am.
- 你能走吗? - 能
- Can you move? - Yes.
好
Okay.
太好了 我们走
Yeah, okay. All right, let's go.
- 起来 - 让我们看看你有什么
- Get off. - Let's see what you got here.
不错
Nice.
该死
Goddamn.
既然你不需要 我就要了
I'm having these babies, seeing as you ain't gonna need them anymore.
没问题 我要问你几个问题
All right, I'm gonna ask you a few questions.
你应该给我答案
You're gonna give me answers.
答错了 你就死
If they're not the right answers, you will die.
为什么你会在这儿
Why are you here?
观察鸟类
Bird watching.
不 让他住手！
Stop him!
- 不关他的事 你们冲我来！ - 把她带出去
- This is not his fight. It's mine. - Get her out of here.
封锁这座楼！
Seal the building.
真是条硬汉 对不对?
You're a real tough guy, aren't you?
什么?
What?
时间到了
Time's up.
- 巴尼呢? - 现在怎么办?
- Where's Barney? - What's the call?
十分钟内还找不到他
We can't find him in 10 minutes,
我们就沿原路返回
we're going out the same way we came in.
- 不行 - 这是他的意思
- No way. - That's what he'd want.
十分钟！行动
Ten minutes! Let's go.
嗨 你叫什么名字?
Hi. What's your name?
- 玩的开心吧 伙计? - 是啊 还不坏
- You having fun yet, mate? - Yeah, not bad.
就我本人而言 很高兴你回来
Personally, I'm glad you came back.
是吗
Yeah?
让他起来
Get him up.
让他站起来
Stand him up.
如果没有这件防弹衣
You know, if you didn't have this Kevlar vest,
你里面会变成一团浆糊
your insides are gonna be like fucking mush.
是吗?
Well, ain't that sad?
你真走运
You know, you're a lucky man.
你也走运了
You're the lucky man.
不 不 你走运了
No, no, you're a lucky man.
- 他让我别把你打昏过去 - 是吗?
- He told me to keep you conscious. - Did he?
好吧
All right. All right.
我给你最后一次机会
Now this is your last time.
对我说实话 我给你一个痛快
You give me the right answer, and I'll cut you a break.
如果敢骗我 我让你生不如死
If you give me the wrong answer, you will die a damn slow death.
明白吗?
Do you understand me?
- 明白吗? - 明白
- Do you understand me? - Yep.
- 谁派你来的? - 我没法呼吸
- Who sent you? - Can't breathe.
松开
Loosen up.
谁派你来的?
Who sent you?
你的理发师
Your hairdresser.
你很不错
You're good.
走 我们走！
Go, we gotta go!
来啊
Come on.
该死！
Shit!
记住这把枪！
Remember this shit at Christmas!
奶奶的 这玩意太响了
Damn, that thing's loud.
- 你怎么了? - 被人扁了
- What happened to you? - I got my ass kicked.
该死 很疼啊
Damn, that stings!
好好享受吧
Suck it up!
把我的枪给我 我们走
Come on. Get my rifle. Let's go.
什么意思?
What's this?
一切的祸乱都是你带来的
Everything bad that has happened, you bring.
拿着你的钱！
Take your money!
和你合作死路一条 拿上钱 离开这！
I only see death with you. Take it all and go.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
这里不欢迎你
You are done here.
没我 你成不了事
You can't succeed without me.
这里我做主
I am the leader.
你就是个傀儡
You're a puppet in a hat.
不要
No.
我应该像你一样
行动！
Now!
回去
Get back.
太老套了！
This shit's getting old.
放下你们的武器
Throw down your weapons.
你们逃不掉的
There's no way out.
- 你的幸运戒指真没用 - 我知道
- Your lucky ring stinks. - I know.
- 我们原路返回 - 整栋楼都被包围了
- Let's backtrack. - The building's rigged.
只有这条路
It's the only way out.
这些美国侵略者想要毁掉我们的国家
直升飞机五分钟后就可以起飞了
Chopper's ready in five minutes.
等一会再走
We're not leaving yet.
原谅我 原谅我的贪婪 我的自私
- 他在说什么? - 他说我们死定了
- What's he saying? - He said we're dead with an accent.
我们不会死的
We ain't dead.
- 炸掉这座楼 - 还没到时候
- Blow the building. - Not yet.
我们要杀死这些美国病毒
We will kill this American disease.
开火！
炸楼！
Blow the building!
她还在里面！
She's still in there!
拿上钱！
The money!
快炸！
Blow it!
她出来了 快炸了这他妈的楼！
She's out. Blow the fucking building!
没子弹了！
I'm out!
我们走 快
Let's go. Come on.
截住芒罗
Cut Munroe off!
来啊！
Come on!
嘿
Hey!
- 东西太重了 - 给我
- Thing's too heavy. - Give me it.
- 你想让我干什么? - 能扔多远扔多远
- What do you want me to do? - Throw it as hard as you can.
- 炸掉仓库 - 明白！
- Blow the dump. - Got it!
芒罗
Munroe!
放下武器 不然我打爆她的头
Drop the weapons, or I'll put a bullet through her eye.
我说到做到
Don't test me.
不要 不
No, no, no.
闭嘴 不然宰了你
Shut up or I'll kill you.
是中情局的人雇你们的 是吗?
The agency parasites hired you, didn't they?
为我干 你们可以轻轻松松拿双倍的钱
I'd have paid you twice as much to go fishing.
你们以为我会那么傻
You'd have to think I'm pretty freaking stupid
向中情局投降
to surrender to the agency.
我为什么要这么做? 是我一手建起了这些
Why would I do that? I created this. I made it all happen.
他们想踢开我 为什么? 因为我比他们更有远见
And then they wanted me out. Why? Because I saw the big picture.
不像她父亲 你 还有中情局
Unlike people like her father, you, the agency,
你的眼界太狭隘了
you see life through a freaking keyhole
因为感情影响了你的判断
because you let emotions cloud your judgment.
感情是理智的天敌
Emotions are the cancer of the intellect!
别过来
Stop walking.
你和我呢?我们是一类人
And what about me and you? We're both the same.
我们都唯利是图 我们的灵魂都死了
We're both mercenaries. We're both dead inside.
你究竟为什么要杀我?
So why the hell did you come after me?
我不是为了你 蠢货 我是为了她
I didn't come after you, dipshit. I came for her!
- 你没事吧? - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
我们打平了
Call it a tie.
算是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
你没你想像的那么快
You know, you're not as fast as you think.
我也感觉到了
I'm beginning to sense that.
第二个账号是我的 帮你们重建家园
The second account number's mine. It'll help get things going around here.
不行 我不能要 你已经帮了我们很多
No, I can't. You've done so much.
你也帮了我 礼尚往来 拿着吧
Yeah, well, so have you. A gift for a gift. You take it.
- 你还会回来吗? - 我一定会回来的
- Will you come back? - I promise I'll always be around.
保重
Take care.
干嘛?
What?
让我说实话吗?
Truthfully?
是啊?
Yeah?
我觉得她不适合你
I never really thought she was your type.
好的 宝贝 好的
All right, baby. All right.
来吧 显显身手
Come on, let's see what you got.
好样的！
That's my boy!
不行喽！
Go south!
你输了！你输了！
You lost! You lost!
在鬼门关打了一回转 伤好了吗?
So you're back from the dead. How you healing?
很好 你放了我一马
Good, considering you could have killed me.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
好的
Okay.
我本来可以打赢你
I would have win.
不可能
Never.
嘿 根拿
Hey, Gunner.
大难不死必有后福 兄弟 别忘了治疗
Whatever doesn't kill you makes you stronger, brother. Therapy.
- 他说什么? - 他说去治疗
- What's he saying? - He said try therapy.
他说的没错
Man's got a point.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我送你一样东西 杜尔
I'm gonna do you a favor, Tool.
“我以前认识一叫杜尔的人”
"I once knew a man called Tool..."
我喜欢诗
I love poetry.
“在我看来 这人就是酷的化身”
"To me, was the epitome of cool
“他是个刀中行家”
"He was good with a knife
“却是个情场输家…”
"Bad with a wife..."
真毒舌
That hurts.
“他以为能打败我”
"But to think he could beat me
“连做梦都想打败我”
"Dreaming he'd defeat me
“酷杜尔”
"Cool Tool
“你真傻”
"You gotta be a fool"
看招
Oh, yeah.
《敢死队》